

# Paulo Lima

Node.js | React | Full-stack

github.com/limapaulo-dev

© +5544998752400

⋈ contact@limapaulo.com

# limapaulo.com

# Summary

I'm a proficient full-stack developer, specialize in coding engaging and responsive interfaces, using modern code technologies to deliver clean, efficient and scalable solutions.

Also I'm a expert in business negotiations, with +15 years of experience working with B2B clients to guide decisions and resolve conflicts.

# > Experience

Health Care Sales Manager - Team adviser • Associate • Private contractor

(2007 - 2023)

From 2007 to 2023 I've established and operated a insurance business that merged with 3 other companies in 2019. In that time I developed my initial software solutions to attract new customers, automate day-to-day tasks, and enhance the efficiency of the business.

- QML-Pricing Created a windows app that automated health insurance calculations and results-sharing for B2B and B2C customers. Speed up price quoting by 95% with 100% accuracy.
- Helped countless customers make informed decisions working 15 yoe in health care insurance sector.
- Negotiated and secured contracts with companies of +2000 employees, both remote or in-person. And performed product presentations to audiences of all sizes.
- Manage a team of over 29 brokers, organizing schedules, training, resolving conflicts and also keeping track of the business sales and performance metrics.

Fullstack Developer - Node.js • React • JavaScript • Python • PHP

( 2022 - Present )

- pradoestates.co.uk Created a website to generate potential leads and improve the SEO rankings for a London-based company, used Wordpress to give the client easy control of the page content.
- WhatsAppDirect Created a web app using asynchronous Javascript to reduce the page load time also reducing the code size by 76%. Used Bootstrap v5.3 for the page responsiveness and material design.
- Developed clean, innovative front-end and back-end web solutions that captivate users, while also adhering to the best practices for writing maintainable and scalable code.
- Skillfully communicated with clients to keep the project scope and ensure satisfaction with the final product.

#### Skills

#### Leadership & Teamwork

Results-focused • Collaborative • Communicative • Mediator

#### Syntaxes & Frameworks

React • Node.JS • MongoDB • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • Bootstrap • Python • PHP • QT/QML

## **Version Control & Productivity**

Scrum • Kanban • Jira • Git • Github • VSC

## Spoken Languages

Portuguese (native) • English (fluent) • Spanish (conversation)

## Education

Bachelor of Internet Systems (2019 - 2022)

Unicesumar • Maringá-PR • Brazil

MBA of Strategic Business Management (2016 - 2018)

Unicesumar • Maringá-PR • Brazil

Bachelor of Business Administration (2012 - 2016)

UEM • Maringá-PR • Brazil